Before looking at a couple of applications for DBSCAN,
在看一些关于 DBSCAN 的应用例子之前
let's discuss its advantages and disadvantages.
我们先来讨论一下它的优缺点
The first advantage of using DBSCAN is that we
使用 DBSCAN 的第一个优点是
don't need to specify the number of clusters.
我们不需要指明类的数量
DBSCAN will just find them based on how densely
DBSCAN 能根据点的分布密度
packed the points are and the other inputs that we pass into it,
以及我们输入的其他指令 如邻域或点的最小数量
namely epsilon and minimum number of points.
从而找到类
The second advantage of DBSCAN is flexibility in
DBSCAN 的第二个优点是
the shapes and sizes of clusters it's able to find and carve out.
能灵活的找到并分离各种形状和大小的类
So DBSCAN is not limited to a certain shape;
DBSCAN 不局限于某种外形的类
it can trace out densely packed points as long as
只要点的密度能形成外形
the density is continued into pretty much any shape.
它就能描绘出这些集群点的形状
And, finally, it's robust in that it's able to deal with
最后 它能够强有力的处理
noise and outliers in the data sets that we pass to it.
我们传递的数据集中的噪声和离群值
On the other hand, there are a couple of nitpicks that we can say about DBSCAN.
另一方面 DBSCAN 也有一些小缺陷
The first one is that border points that are reachable from two clusters
第一个缺点就是 从两个类可达的边界点
are assigned to the cluster that finds them
被分配给了另一个类 因为这个类先发现的这个边界点
first and since points are visited in an arbitrary order,
由于各个点是被随机拜访的
DBSCAN is not guaranteed to return the same clustering if this is the case.
如果出现这种情况的话 DBSCAN 不能保证传回相同的聚类
Thankfully though, most datasets do not face this issue.
尽管如此 幸运的是大多数数据集不会面临这个问题
The second disadvantage for DBSCAN is that it faces
DBSCAN 的第二个缺点是
difficulties finding clusters of varying densities.
在找到不同密度的类方面有一定的困难
For cases like that, however,
然而 针对这样的情况
we can use a variation of DBSCAN called HDBSCAN.
我们可以用 DBSCAN 的变体 HDBSCAN 即具有噪声的基于密度的高层次空间聚类算法
There're links to it in the text below the video.
视频下方的文本中有相关链接
And now we can look at a couple of really cool applications for DBSCAN.
现在我们可以看几个 DBSCAN 应用的范例
This is one paper that looks at
这篇论文研究的是网络流量
network traffic and tries to classify it using clustering algorithms.
试图用聚类算法将其分类
So, let's say you're a network administrator and you have people
假如说你是一个网络管理员
running BitTorrent on your network and you want to classify traffic,
发现人们在你的网络上运行比特流 你想对流量进行分类
is it BitTorrent, is it just regular web traffic,
一类是比特流 一类是常规网络流量
especially if you can't peek at the actual packets themselves and tell.
特别是你没有办法看到实际的包从而得到判断
This paper compares k-means and DBSCAN in this classification,
这篇论文比较了在这个分类下的 K-均值聚类法和 DBSCAN
the unsupervised classification of network traffic.
即网络流量的非监督分类
This graph here shows the accuracy of
这份图标展示了 基于不同的邻域值
that classification based on different epsilon distance values,
所得到的分类的准确率
and in here we can look at different epsilon distance value as well as
这儿 我们能看到不同的邻域值
different minimum number of points value and then how that
不同的点的最小数量
affects the accuracy of the classification.
以及二者对分类准确性产生的影响
Another cool example is this paper doing
另外一个范例是
anomaly detection in temperature data using DBSCAN.
这篇论文用 DBSCAN 对温度数据做异常检测
And the way to do that is to set minimum number of points and epsilon
方法是 设定点的最小数量以及邻域值
to values that group most of the samples in the dataset into one or a few clusters.
从而让数据集中的大多数数据能分成一个或几个类
And then the points that are labeled as noise we
对于被标记为噪声的点
would regard these as outliers or anomalies.
我们把它们看做离群值或者异常
And by changing minimum number of points and epsilon we can
通过改变点的最小数量和邻域值
change how permissive or aggressive we want the anomaly detection to be.
我们能够改变这个异常检测的许可度或攻击性
You can find links to these two papers in the links below but specifically,
大家可以在下方的链接中找到这两篇论文的链接
I really loved reading this network traffic paper because it shows you the methodology
我非常喜欢这篇网络流量的论文 因为它用完整的思维过程
of clustering from the beginning to the end with a thought process that goes into it.
从头到尾完整地展示了聚类方法的流程
It's a really cool example.
是一个非常棒的例子
I advise you, go through this paper
我建议大家读一下这篇论文